Aron Trauring

email: <u>atrauring@zoteca.com</u> phone: +1 (917) 496-6240 cell: +972-54-992-7866

PROFILE

I have worked over 35 years for high-tech companies in the US and abroad. I served in senior positions doing technical development and software project management — I was one of the original developers of Statemate, a statechart simulation tool (Statecharts are now part of the Unified Modeling Language). I also served in senior positions doing international sales and marketing for major high tech companies. A serial entrepreneur, I co-founded one of the earliest successful interactive media agencies, an Internet B2B services company, a software startup which developed a patented data security/privacy platform and a social enterprise startup.

EXPERIENCE

CIO, EMELAI; TEL AVIV, ISRAEL — 2016-PRESENT

Emelai is a technology startup that applies the latest research in neuropsychology together with Machine Learning/Al cognitive computing, to help our customers develop positive habit formation in users of their digital platforms. Responsible for developing and leading the implementation of the cloud, security and software architecture of our products.

CEO AND CO-FOUNDER, ZOTECA; NEW YORK, NY — 2000-PRESENT

Founded a software startup, Zoteca and raised seed investment to develop a patent for the secure and robust exchange of data in distributed environments. In the post-9/11 recession climate, migrated the company to become a successful boutique consultancy, providing customers a Software Development Team in a Box.

CEO AND CO-FOUNDER, EBO NEXUS; NEW YORK, NY — 2013-2014

Our mission was to create technology that helps low-income people easily connect to the supplemental benefits they deserve. Since 2009 our product helped over 120,000 households connect to over \$350 million in supplemental benefits. The project was a spin-off from development work at Zoteca. The company was established as an independent company in 1/2013.

INSTRUCTOR, CUNY T++/SCHOOL OF PROFESSIONAL STUDIES; NEW YORK, NY — 2005-2009

Developed and taught courses on the following topics: Software Project Management: An Agile Approach, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Internet Technologies and Open Source Security Tools.

INSTRUCTOR, NETCOM INFORMATION SYSTEMS; NEW YORK, NY — 2005-2011

Taught Ubuntu and Novell/Suse Linux: Linux+, Linux System Administration, Linux Network Administrator

CEO AND CO-FOUNDER, MAXIMA NEW MEDIA; KFAR SAVA, ISRAEL — 1994-2000

Established and managed MAXIMA, a world-class, award-winning interactive agency that specialized in the area of culture. Among its clients were Beth Hatefutsoth and the Israel Museum in Israel and the Memorial Foundation in New York. MAXIMA reached over \$1 million in annual billings.

DIRECTOR OF EUROPEAN SALES, AMDOCS; TEL AVIV, ISRAEL — 1990-1993

Aron Trauring Resume 1 of 3

Responsible for developing the European market for a \$100 million systems integration and information technology company. Reported directly to one of AMDOCS founders, the Senior VP for Sales & Marketing.

MANAGER INTERNATIONAL CUSTOMERS OPERATIONS, I-LOGIX; SLOUGH, ENGLAND / BOSTON, MA — 1988-1990

Responsible for marketing, sales and support of STATEMATE (a high-level systems specification and testing tool) in international markets. Helped create a worldwide distribution network. Brought sales to a level of \$1.5 million, representing over 50% of the company's revenues.

SENIOR PROJECT MANAGER, I-LOGIX (AD-CAD); REHOVOT, ISRAEL — 1983-1988

One of the company's first employees. Responsible for managing several critical projects, including porting STATEMATE to new workstation platforms. Actively involved in the establishment of a new marketing organization in the U.S. which became i-Logix.

SENIOR SYSTEM SPECIALIST, SEED SOFTWARE; PHILADELPHIA, PA — 1980-1983

Participated in the development of new products and the enhancement of existing ones for a Codasyl-DBMS package.

ADMINISTRATIVE SERVICES ANALYST., ARTHUR ANDERSEN; PHILADELPHIA, PA — 1979-1980Participated in all phases of small and large scale IT projects.

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania; Philadelphia, PA Moore School of Electrical Engineering, *Course work only*, 1980-1981

Carnegie Mellon University; Pittsburgh, PA School of Urban and Public Affairs (SUPA) *M.S. Public Management*, May 1979

Columbia College; New York, NY, B.A. Urban Studies, May 1975

AWARDS

One of the recipients of the <u>ACM 2007 Software System Award</u>. This is "[a]warded to an institution or individual(s) recognized for developing a software system that has had a lasting influence, reflected in contributions to concepts, in commercial acceptance, or both. For Statemate, the first embodiment in a commercial computer-aided software engineering tool of a rigorous approach to model-driven development based on statecharts, and employing techniques for the executability of visual formalisms, and for code-generation."

SKILLS

With a long and varied career I have acquired a wide range of diverse skills. My key talent, which I apply in whatever I do, is being a great problem solver. Whether dealing with internal team conflicts, crashed servers, getting a customer to sign a contract or squashing a software bug, I have an innate ability to quickly analyze a problem and break it down into components, and then synthesize and implement an effective solution.

Aron Trauring Resume 2 of 3

From my years in marketing and sales I learned how to be an effective communicator, both as a speaker and writer. I also came to understand that success requires one to take a customer perspective and focus on people more than technology. I apply these skills when I work with potential and existing customers, stand in front of a class, lead a team meeting or report to customers about project progress and pitfalls.

From my years in managing software projects both in other companies and my own, I have learned that success means delivering working software that meets customer needs. By focusing on that criterion I consistently deliver successful projects on time and on budget.

From my years in leading technology teams, I know that I must be as familiar with technology as any team member. Over the years what's hot in technology has changed but I have led teams in various projects ranging over machine learning/AI, big data & BI applications, iOS & Android apps & expert systems. I am also experienced in the latest agile development processes as well as DevOps automation approaches & technologies.

My current tech tools include heavy use of the following:

Programming Languages: Scala, Python

Scripting: Python, Bash

Web: HTML, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap

Internet: Apache, NGinx, SSL, DNS, SSH, VPN

Operating System Management & Security: OS X, Windows & Windows Server, Linux (Amazon,

Ubuntu & Fedora)

Big Data Tool Management: Spark, R/RStudio, Jupyter

Database: MongoDB and to a lesser extent PostgreSQL

Cloud Platform Deployment, Management & Security: AWS , Azure, Office 365, and to a lesser

extent IBM BlueMix

Developer Tools: Intellij, Git, Github, JIRA, Confluence, SBT

Misc: Power Bl, Anaconda

Other tech tools in the process/pipeline of acquiring: AWS/Azure/IBM Watson cognitive services, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Vagrant, Packer, Microsoft Team Services (CI/CD), Bintray, Open API Initiative (Swagger), SQL Server, DocumentDB

Aron Trauring Resume 3 of 3